Coach Marumo. We're ready.
（友樹・薫）マルモ監督 お願いします。
Okay. Keep your eyes open and watch the ball.
（護）おし。　じゃ　目　開いて よ～く　球　見んだぞ。→
First up is Kaoru. Let's go.
まずは薫選手　いってみよう。
What was that? We're not playing volleyball, you know.
（護）何だよ バレーボールじゃねえんだぞ。
However, that was nice play that you let it drop in front of you.
ただし　前に落としたのはナイス。
Thank you.
（薫）ありがとうございます。→
Oh, there's Hayato-kun.
あっ　隼人君だ。
Is he your classmate?
んっ？　同級生か？
-He's alone again. -What do you mean again?
（友樹）また１人だ。 またって何だよ。
Hayato-kun's daddy and mommy are busy
（薫）隼人君ちは パパもママも忙しいから→
so he's always playing by himself.
いつも１人で遊んでるの。
Then go see if he wants to join us, Kaoru.
へえ。　じゃ　薫　誘ってこいよ。
-Is it okay? -Two or three, same difference.
（薫・友樹）いいの？ ああ　２人も３人も一緒だ。
-I'll coach you all. -Yes, Coach.
まとめて教えてやるよ。 はい　監督。
Hayato-kun.
隼人く～ん。
Huh? Hayato-kun?
あれ？　隼人君？
Marumo, we're gonna be late if we don't get going.
マルモ そろそろ行かないと遅刻しちゃう。
I know. We're almost done, so just hang in there.
分かってる　すぐ終わるから もうちょっと待ってなさいよ。
Tomoki, finish eating now. I tell you, we're going to be late.
友樹　もう　ごちそうさまして。 遅刻しちゃうってば。
-Hey, don't move. -I'm done eating.
動くなよ　おい。 ごちそうさまでした。
Okay, done.
よし　できた。
-They're uneven. -Are they?
（ムック）曲がってんじゃん。 んっ？　そうか？
Look, if you look at it like this, it's even. Right?
ほら　こうやって見れば　ほら 真っすぐだろ。　なっ。
-Yeah. -Yeah, thanks.
うん。 うん　ありがとう。
We're going. -Okay, see you later.
いってきます。 あいよ　いってらっしゃい。
I tell you, they're uneven.
やっぱり曲がってるって。
It's the thought that counts.
ああいうのはな 気持ちの問題なんだよ。
Safe.
セーフ。
Oh, there's Hayato-kun.
あっ　隼人君だ。
Hayato-kun, why did you leave yesterday?
隼人君 昨日は何で帰っちゃったの？
Coach Marumo was gonna teach us catch.
マルモ監督が　キャッチボール 教えてくれるって言ったのに。
You're always alone, aren't you? Come practice with us.
隼人君　いつも１人でしょ？ 薫たちと一緒にやろうよ。
What?
（隼人）えっ？
Hayato, you're gonna play catch with a girl?
（健太）隼人 女とキャッチボールすんのか？
No, I'm not.
そっ　そんなの　やらないよ。
-Why? -Because.
どうして？ （隼人）どうしても。
Playing catch is fun.
キャッチボール　面白いよ。
Be quiet, Sasa Buta*. (*Buta = pig)
うるさい　ささブタ。
-You're Sasakura so you're Sasa Buta. -I'm not a pig.
笹倉だから　ささブタじゃん。 豚じゃない。
Hayato-kun, her name's Sasakura Kaoru, not Sasa Buta.
隼人君 ささブタじゃなくて　笹倉　薫。
Sasa Buta Gaoru. (Ga oru - literally, is here, ie., Sasa Buta is here)
ささブタがおる。
He said Sasa Buta is here.
（健太）ささブタがおるだって。
Sasa Buta Gaoru.
（隼人）ささブタがおる。
-But I'm not a pig. -Sasa Buta Gaoru.
豚じゃないもん。
Hey, don't run around in the classroom.
（杉下）こら 教室で走るんじゃない。→
-You could get hurt. -But Hayato-kun...
危ないだろ。 だって隼人君が。
No excuses.
（杉下）はい　もう言い訳しない。
Sasakura-san, hurry up and sit down.
笹倉さんも早く席に着きなさい。
-Takagi-san? -What? Oh.
（かな）高木さん？ あれ？　あっ。
-Hello. -Makimura-san, hello.
（かな）あっ　お疲れさまです。 牧村さん　お疲れさまです。
Thank you for helping me out the other day.
あっ 先日は　ありがとうございました。
Are you alright now?
（かな）あっ　もう大丈夫ですか？
Yes. I'm sorry for asking you for such a strange favor.
ええ　すいませんでした 急に　変な　お願いしちゃって。
To ask you to pretend to be my fiancee
婚約者のふりだなんて→
was such a impertinent, no, bold, request.
ずうずうしいというか もう　大胆な　お願いを。
Although I was a little nervous since I've never acted before.
お芝居なんてしたことないから 少し緊張しましたけど。
I'm very disappointed and regret that I didn't get to see it with my own eyes.
いや　この目で見られなかったのが非常に残念で無念です。
-Makimura-san. -Yes.
牧村さん。 はい。
Um...If it's okay with you, I'd like to thank you.
あの　もし　よろしかったら その　お礼がしたいんですけど→
Um... Would you like to go to dinner sometime?
あっ　あの 今度　お食事でもいかがですか？
It's alright if you don't want to. It's perfectly alright if you don't want to.
いや　駄目ならいいんです 駄目なら全然いいんです。
-I would love to. -Really?
はい　ぜひ　お願いします。 ホントですか？
But don't leave me behind this time, okay?
でも　今度は 置き去りにしないでくださいね。
Huh? Did that ever happen?
あれ？ そんなことありましたっけ？
-It did, didn't it? -It did... I'm sorry.
ありましたよね。 ありま…　すいません。
That won't happen again. Never, never again.
もう二度としません。 ネバー　ネバーありません。
Sorry.
あっ　すっ　すいません。
Hey, do you guys remember Makimura-san?
ねえ　お前らさ 牧村さんって覚えてる？
Oh, the onee-san who came here when Marumo had the mumps?
あっ　マルモが おたふくのとき来た　お姉さん？
-Tomoki, you're right. -Yes!
友樹君　正解。 よっしゃ。
I have a dinner engagement with Makimura-san.
その牧村さんと今度 会食してくるから。
-What's dinner engagement? -That's, you know, dinner?
会食って何？ あっ　だから　その　食事会？
To put it simply, it's a d-date.
いやいや　分かりやすく言うと デッ　デート。
-Date? -Is that an overstatement?
デート？ 言い過ぎか？
Maybe a date is an overstatement?
デートは言い過ぎちゃったかな？ ハハハハハ。
-Too overjoyed. -Who, me?
浮かれ過ぎ。 んっ？　俺がか　おい。　なっ。
What's that mood there. Is something wrong, Kaoru-chan?
あれ？　何　その感じ。 薫ちゃん　どうかしたのかい？
Um... Today, Hayato-kun...
え～と お姉ちゃんが　今日　隼人君に。
It's nothing. It's nothing.
何でもない　何でもない。
What, say what's on your mind.
何だよ　正直に言えよ。
Really, it's nothing.
本当に何でもない。
Hey, we have an okite to say what's on our mind.
おい　言いたいことは言うって おきてだろ？
Hayato-kun called me Sasa Buta.
隼人君が　薫のこと　ささブタって。
You got teased?
からかわれたのか。
He changed Sasakura to Sasa Buta.
笹倉をささブタと。
He said Sasa Buta Gaoru.
ささブタがおるだって。
Isn't he horrible?
ひどいでしょ？
That's pretty good for a first grader. Huh?
いや　小１にしてはセンスあるな。 なっ。　ハハハハハ。
-It's not funny. -Listen, Kaoru.
面白くない。 あのな　薫→
It's a habit for the boys to tease the girls.
男子は 女子をからかうのが癖なの。
When boys see cute girls, they just get the urge to tease them.
カワイイ子を見ると からかいたくなっちゃうもんなの。
-That's disgusting. -Hey, that's not disgusting,
最低。 最低って　お前→
that's just a practical joke. That's togetherness. Okay?
単なる悪ふざけだよ。 スキンシップなの。　なっ。
You have to let it go. Just ignore it.
軽く受け流しゃいいんだよ。 無視しろ　無視。
Takagi-san, you just don't understand.
（彩）うわ～ 高木さん　全然　分かってない。→
Kaoru-chan will be even more hurt if you say it like that.
そんな言い方したら 薫ちゃん　余計　傷つきますよ。
She was just teased, you know.  If she gets upset every time she's teased...
ちょっと　からかわれただけだよ？そんなこと気にしてたらさ。
It's a very serious problem for girls.
（彩）女の子には 深刻な問題なんです。
And there you go, saying things like let it go and ignore it,
それを 受け流せとか無視しろとか→
the very things you shouldn't be saying.
一番やっちゃいけない パターンですよ。
Aya-san's right. You don't understand at all.
≪（真島）彩さんの言うとおり。 全然　分かってない。
Why are you here?
お前　何で　こんなとこにいんだよ。
Can't you see? I'm drinking shochu.
（真島）見れば分かるでしょ 焼酎を飲んでるんですよ。
He's been coming quite often recently.
（彩）あっ 最近　よく来てくれるんです。
He's a regular customer. Right?
常連さん。　ねえ。
He lives in the complete opposite direction, you know. It's really far from here.
ねえ　こいつんち　まったく 逆方向だよ。　すごい遠いよ。
I don't think distance has anything to do with it.
（真島）いや 距離は関係ないでしょ。→
But leaving that aside, Takagi-san, you don't know women at all.
そんなことより高木さんはね 女心を知らな過ぎるんですよ。→
I bet you've been insensitive since you were a kid.
子供のころから デリカシーなかったんだろうな。
How am I supposed to know girls' feelings. I'm a boy.
女子の気持ちなんか分かるかよ。 だって　俺　男子だもん。
Woah. He's assuming a defiant attitude.
（彩）わ～　開き直った。
I'm not being defiant. It's the truth, isn't it?
開き直ってないでしょ 事実でしょ？
Enough about this already.
あ～　もう　この話　いいですよ。
Just now, you were thinking this is a pain, didn't you?
あっ　今 めんどくせえって思ったでしょ。→
That's not a good attitude, you know.
そういう態度　良くないですよ。
Pops, give me a beer.
親父さん　ビール。 （陽介）はいよ。
Ignoring. Ignoring is the worst thing to do. That's definitely the worst.
（彩）無視。　無視は　一番　駄目です。さすがに最低です。→
Takagi-san, you're not gonna be able to marry if you don't change your ways.
あっ　高木さん そんなんじゃ結婚できませんよ。
Even if by chance you find a wife, she's going to leave you.
万が一　お嫁さん　もらっても 逃げられちゃいますよ。
If by chance?
万が一？
Aren't all men like that?
（陽介）男なんてのはな そういうもんじゃねえの？
Generally speaking,
えっ？ （陽介）だいたいな→
if you don't have an open mind to accept that kind of things,
そういうのを受け入れる その広い心がないと→
-you just might fail. -Fail...what?
失敗したりするんだよ。 （彩）失敗って…　あれ？
What are you insinuating?
（陽介）んっ？ （彩）当て付けてます？
-Nothing. -Insinuating? Insinuating?
（陽介）全然。 （真島）当て付け？　当て付け？
Dad, are you thinking that I was at fault?
（彩）お父さん わたしが悪いと思ってんの？
Well, I wasn't. He's the one
違います。 あいつが　外で　こそこそ→
-who was sneaking around with a woman. -He? Who's he?
女つくってたの。 あいつって　どいつだ？
Just because he fooled around once,
あのな １回　浮気されたぐらいで→
-isn't it a bit harsh to unilaterally cut off all ties? -Cut off what ties?
三くだり半はないんじゃないか？ 三くだり半って何。
Can you be quiet for a while, please?
（彩）ちょっ 静かにしてもらえます？→
Once. -What do you mean once?
１回ぐらい。 １回ぐらいって　どういうこと？
All I'm saying is you should forgive him for that one time.
だから それぐらいは許してやりゃいいの。
I can't believe what you just said.
ハァ　その言い方。→
Takagi-san, don't turn out to be like him.
高木さん こうはならないでくださいね。→
You have to listen to what Kaoru-chan has to say.
薫ちゃんの話 ちゃんと聞いてあげてくださいよ。
Yes.
はい。
-Rinka-chan. -Yes?
凛花ちゃん。 （凛花）はい？
Were you ever teased by boys when you were little?
子供のころにさ　男子に からかわれたことってある？
Of course I was.
（凛花）そんなの もちろんありますよ。→
All the girls were, weren't they?
女子は みんなあるんじゃないですか？
Would that be considered an unpleasant experience?
それって　やっぱり 嫌なことなのかな。
That goes without saying. What?
（民子）当たり前じゃない。　えっ？
Didn't you even know that, Takagi-kun?
そんなことから分かってないの？ 高木君。
Takagi-san's just now learning now that he's almost 40.
高木さんは今　４０を手前にして やっと学んでるんですよ。
How do I explain it.
（凛花）何て言うのかな。→
It felt like I was stepped on all over by someone's shoes.
土足で全身を踏まれたような気に なりましたね。
-Muddy shoes at that too. -It's that bad?
（民子）しかも泥だらけの土足でね。そんなに？
Takagi-kun was one of the boys who teased, huh?
高木君も からかうタイプの男子だったんだ。
Yes. I did tease all the girls I liked, so?
はい　好きだって思う女子は 全員　からかってましたけど？
Why do you tease them if you like them?
（凛花）うわっ　好きなのに 何で　からかうんですか？
Don't you tease them because you like them?
好きだから からかうんじゃないの？
What's that supposed to mean.
（凛花）何それ。　意味　分かんない。 えっ。
-Takagi-kun. -Yes.
（鮫島）高木君。 はい。
-Can I see you for a minute?
（鮫島）ちょっといい？
I'm going to visit a regular customer tomorrow. Let's go together.
（鮫島）あした　お得意さまのところ行くんだけど　一緒に行こうよ。→
-It will be a good learning experience for you. -A regular customer?
勉強になるから。 お得意さま？
Yes. Last month's reports. Go over them, okay?
（鮫島）そう　これ先月の報告書。 目　通しといてね。
Yes.
あっ　はい。
What's a regular customer? Is it a customer who complains regularly?
お得意さまってさ　何？ クレームのお得意さまってこと？
I've never met this person, but
僕　会ったことないですけど→
Samejima-san goes for a visit once in a while by himself.
鮫島さん 時々１人で出掛けてくんですよ。
Personally?
直々に？
Maybe he's planning to
そのお得意さんを→
have Takagi-san take over that regular customer?
高木さんに引き継ぐつもり なんじゃないですか？
Does that mean I'm going to be dealing with him instead?
えっ 俺が代わりに相手するってこと？
By telling you to go over the reports
報告書に 目　通しとけってことは→
isn't he telling you to use discretion in your interaction?
それだけ 慎重に対応しろってことでしょ？
-That's scary. -But why me?
怖っ。 ちょっと　何で俺なんだよ。
Athlete Kaoru, here it comes.
薫選手　いくぞ。
Bring it on.
さあ　こい。
I can't catch it if you don't throw it here.
あっ　ここに投げてくれないと 捕れないよ。
You're hopeless.
下手くそ。
Give it back. We're practicing on our own. Coach Marumo told us to.
返してよ　自主練なんだから。 マルモ監督に言われたの。
He's just telling you to practice on your own because he got tired of playing with you.
自主練なんて　相手するのが 面倒になったからだよ。
Marumo isn't your real dad, is he?
だって　マルモは 本当のパパじゃないんだろ？
Marumo is Marumo.
マルモはマルモだもん。
If he's not your dad, why are you living with him?
パパじゃないのに どうして一緒に住んでるんだよ。
That's because we're family.
それは　家族だからだよ。
That's weird that he's family even though he's not your dad.
パパじゃないのに家族なんて 変だよ。
He'll get tired of you right away and abandon you.
すぐに飽きて捨てられちゃうね。
Marumo won't do that.
マルモは　そんなことしない。
Pretty soon he's gonna start saying he's too busy at work
仕事が忙しいからって 子供だけで　ご飯　食べたり→
and make the kids eat and go to sleep by themselves.
子供だけで寝たりするように なるんだよ。
He's not going to be playing catch with you either.
キャッチボールだって もう　してもらえないよ。
The ball.
あっ　ボール。
Marumo's gonna abandon you anyway. Kaoru's gonna be abandoned by Marumo.
どうせマルモに捨てられる。 薫はマルモに捨てられる。
Okay, done. Sit down, guys.
よし　できた。　ほら　お前ら　座れ。
Itadakima~su.
いただきま～す。 はい。
Aren't you eating, Marumo?
マルモは食べないの？
Huh? I don't have time to think about eating right now.
あっ？ 今さ　飯どころじゃねえんだよ。
If I let my guard down, I might be trouble tomorrow.
油断してると あした大変なことになるからな。
Marumo, hang in there.
マルモ　ガッツ出して。
You guys sure have it easy.
お前ら　気楽でいいよな。
I want to clean up soon so
もうさ あの　早く片付けたいからさ→
hurry up and eat.
さっさと食っちゃえよ。 は～い。
I don't feel like eating.
うん。 薫　あんまり食べたくない。
I took time out of my busy schedule to make it, so eat up.
忙しい中　せっかく作ったんだからちゃんと食えよ。
If you're disobedient, I'm gonna kick you out. I'm gonna throw you out with oversize trash.
わがまま言うやつは追い出すぞ。 粗大ごみで出しちゃうからな。
Tomoki.
友樹。
What?
何？
Do you enjoy being with Marumo?
マルモと一緒にいて楽しい？
-A lot. -Me too.
すっごく楽しい。 薫も。
But I wonder if Marumo enjoys being with us.
でも　マルモは薫たちといて 楽しいのかな。
We're always happy but
薫たちは　ずっと楽しいけど→
maybe Marumo doesn't like making meals,
マルモは　ご飯　作ったり お掃除したり→
and cleaning, and working until late at night.
遅くまで　お仕事したり 嫌じゃないのかな。
I don't know.
分かんない。
Okay.
よし。
What happened?
あっ！ えっ　何　どうしたの？
Hey, what are you doing?
あっ　あっ　おい　あちちちちち お前　何やってんだよ　おい。
Something smells.
何か　変な　においがする。
What?
えっ？
Hey, that too?
あち　あち　あちっ　あちっ あっ　あちっ　おい。　こっちも？
I was trying to make breakfast for Marumo.
マルモに 朝ご飯　作ろうと思ったの。
So how did it turn out like this?
それが　何で　こうなるんだよ。
Don't make more work for me. Really.
余計なことしなくていいよ ったく　もう。
What are we going to do with this?
どうすんだよ　これ。
Onee-chan, first period is language.
お姉ちゃん　１時間目　国語だよ。
-Oh, okay. -Good morning, Sasa Buta.
あっ　うん。 ささブタ　おはよう。
Hayato-kun, shh~.
隼人君　し～。
Onee-chan's down because she messed up breakfast.
お姉ちゃんは 朝ご飯　失敗して　落ち込んでるの。
Everything turned out black. Marumo's papers got all black too.
全部　真っ黒。 マルモの書類も真っ黒なんだから。
Tomoki.
友樹。
Did you interfere with his work?
（隼人）もしかして 仕事の邪魔したの？
That's bad. Marumo's gonna abandon you.
最悪じゃん マルモに捨てられるぞ。→
Oh-oh. You're gonna get abandoned.
あ～あ　捨てられる。
-Marumo and Sasa Buta are gonna be separated. -Be quiet.
マルモと　ささブタは　離れ離れ。 うるさい。
Sasa Buta and Marumo are gonna be separated.
（隼人）ささブタとマルモは 離れ離れ。
We're not gonna be separated...
離れ離れじゃな…。
Ouch.
（隼人）痛てて。
Hayato-kun, are you alright?
隼人君　大丈夫？
Tea alright?
（伊達）お茶でいいよね。
Tea's fine. Make it cold.
（鮫島）おお　お茶でいいよ。 冷たいやつ。
You nervous?
あれ？　緊張してる？
But who is that person?
はっ　はっ あの　それより　あの方は？
-Date-chan. -Date-chan?
伊達ちゃん。 伊達ちゃん？
He's a former complainant.
元クレーマーだよ。
Former meaning he's not now?
元ってことは　今　違うんすか？
Shall we say he's now an outside consultant?
今はね　社外相談役？
Actually, I'm just consulting him on my own so
いや　俺の方が 勝手に相談してるだけだから→
maybe he's my private outside consultant.
私設社外相談役かな。→
Anyway, he's done a lot for me.
とにかく世話んなってんだよ。
Considering that, you don't even bring gifts when you visit, do you.
（伊達）その割には　手土産の１つも持ってこねえんだもんな。
A long time ago, I took Date-chan's complaint.
（鮫島）大昔にさ　伊達ちゃんから クレームを受けて。→
Talk about persistent.
これが　また　しつこいんだ。
That's because of the flimsy pencils you guys were making.
（伊達）お前らが やわな鉛筆　作ってっからだよ。
See what I mean?
（鮫島）ヘヘヘヘ ほら　この調子だろ？
Everyone got so scared, no one wanted to deal with him.
ビビって 誰も対応したがらないんだ。
Thanks to me, though, you came up with a sturdy pencil with unbreakable lead, right?
（伊達）おかげで芯の折れない 丈夫な鉛筆になったんじゃねえか。
-Yes, yes. -What happened?
（鮫島）へいへい。 どういうことですか？
He was so persistent that I talked it over with the top
あんまり　しつこいんでさ 上に掛け合って→
and based on Date-chan's complaint, we made a slight improvement to the product.
伊達ちゃんのクレームを基に 商品をちょっと改良したんだよね。
Although it took a long time.
（伊達）まあ 結構　時間かかったけどな。
-It was from that time, huh? -Yeah.
あんときからかな。 （伊達）うん。
That I sometimes discuss the complaints we get
相談室に来たクレームをさ→
at Customer Services with Date-chan.
伊達ちゃんと２人で たまに検討するんだ。
You know, for every complaint we get,
ほら　クレーム１つ取ったって→
our interpretation and theirs are different, right?
こっち側の解釈と 向こう側の解釈じゃ違うだろ？
Ah, so that's what you meant when you told me to review the reports.
あっ　報告書のおさらいって そういう意味だったんすか。
By the way, what happened to the strawberry glue?
（伊達）あっ　いちごのり あれから　どうなったのよ。
The uproar's somewhat under control, but
（鮫島）うん　騒ぎは それなりに収まったんだけど→
-looks like the production will be decreased. -The feeling is that
生産ラインは減らすみたいだね。 いちごのりに関しては→
strawberry glue caused too much commotion.
騒ぎが大きくなり過ぎた感が ありますから。
I bought it for my grandkid too, but
（伊達）うん。　いや うちの孫にも買ってやったらさ→
he found it so amusing, he pasted things like
面白がって チラシでもレシートでも→
flyers and receipts all over the place.
そこらじゅうに はっちまうんだわ。
-Everything got sticky. -We're very sorry for the inconvenience.
べたべたで大変だったよ。 それは大変ご迷惑を。
No, that's okay.
（伊達）いや　いいんだよ　それで。
There aren't too many office supplies that make you want to use it
用もねえのに 使いたくなる文具なんて→
-for no apparent reason. -Well, I suppose.
なかなかねえだろ。 ええ　まあ。
So the production will be decreased, huh?
生産を減らすか。
Seems like a waste to let an opportunity to please the customers slip away
売り手の都合で 客が喜ぶチャンス逃すなんて→
because of the seller's circumstances.
もったいねえな。
Doesn't what he say make sense?
（鮫島）いいこと言うだろ？
Excuse me.
すいません。
It comes down to the fact that our company doesn't handle
（鮫島）でも　うちの社はさ　結局 ああいうファンシー商品って→
-fancy goods like that very well. -So that's what it's about, huh?
あんまり得意じゃないんだよね。 （伊達）ああ　そういうことか。
-Marumo? -Kaoru.
マルモ？ 薫。
Ta-Takagi-san. -Why are you here?
（杉下）たっ　高木さん どっ　どうされたんですか？
Hey. Huh? Where did you get hurt? Are you alright?
おい　あれ？　ケガどうした？ おい　大丈夫か？
Um..that's not it, Takagi-san.
あっ　いや　高木さん　違います。
Taniguchi-san's the one who got injured, and
あの ケガをしたのは谷口さんの方で→
Sasakura-san is the one who caused the injury.
笹倉さんはケガをさせた方でして。
What?
えっ？
The injury's just a light bruise.
まあ ケガと言っても軽い打ち身です。
We had a doctor take a look just to be sure,
一応　病院で 検査してもらったんですが→
but the injury's so minor, you didn't need to come...
大したケガでもないので　わざわざ来ていただかなくってもよかっ…。
Kaoru, did you apologize properly?
薫　ちゃんと謝ったのか？
-Go apologize. -But I didn't do anything wrong.
謝んなさいよ。 でも　薫は悪くないもん。
What do you mean you didn't do anything wrong when you made him get hurt.
ケガさしといて 悪くないってことないだろ。
Go on, apologize.
ほら　謝れって。
Now, now Takagi-san.
（杉下）まあ　まあ　高木さん。
It doesn't sound like Sasakura-san was totally in the wrong
笹倉さんだけが　一方的に 悪いってことでもないようで→
since they were both joking around.
お互いに 悪ふざけしてたみたいなんで。
I'm very sorry.
ホントに　ごめんなさい。
My apology won't do, will it?
俺が謝っても駄目だよね。
It doesn't matter.
（隼人）別にいいです。
What about Hayato-kun's parents?
あの　隼人君の親御さんは？
Due to circumstances at work, they said they couldn't come today.
お仕事の都合で 今日は来れないそうです。
Both of them?
お二人ともですか？
Yes. They must be busy.
（杉下）ええ　お忙しいみたいで。
Kaoru, why didn't you apologize?
薫　何で謝んねえんだよ。
I didn't do anything wrong.
薫は悪くないもん。
You still saying that?
まだ言ってんのかよ。
I know because I apologize every day.
俺は 毎日　謝ってっから　知ってんだよ。
"I'm sorry" opens up the other person's heart.
ごめんなさいは相手の心を開くの。
But I don't want to apologize.
だって　謝りたくない。
When you apologize first,
まず　こっちが謝って→
lot of times that can bring you closer.
そこから仲良くなることだって 多いんだぞ。
I don't care if I'm not close to him.
仲良くならなくていいもん。
I give up then. I'm disappointed in you.
ハァ　もう　面倒　見きれねえ。 がっかりだよ。
-How's Kaoru? -She went to sleep without even eating.
（陽介）薫　どうした？ 飯も食わないで寝ちゃいました。
You say she caused the injury, but wasn't it
でも　ケガさしたって言っても あれだろ？
-like it just happened by chance? -Well, yes.
弾みみたいなもんだったんだろ？ ええ　まあ。
But she won't apologize.
でもね　あいつ謝んないんですよ。
I don't know if she's stubborn or insolent or what.
頑固っていうか 生意気っていうか。
But I'm surprised. I thought she'd be a bit more mature.
しかし意外だな。　もっと お姉ちゃんだと思ったけどな。
She has the nerve to sulk and be miffed.
いつまでも　ぶすっとして むくれやがって。
Really makes me mad.
ホント　ムカつくんですよ。
Why are you laughing?
んっ　何で笑ってんすか？
Being able to sulk and get mad
いや　むくれたり ムカついたりってのは→
means that ...you know. That you're a family.
あれじゃねえか？ 家族だからだ。　なっ。
It's proof that
あれだな　いよいよ→
you're not holding anything back from each other.
遠慮がなくなってきたっていう 証拠だな。
That's a good thing. To be able to say what you want without holding anything back.
いいじゃねえか。　気　使ってねえで言いたいこと言い合って。　なっ。
That's right. Aya-chan and you're like that too.
そうか　親父さんと彩ちゃんも そうですもんね。
-Us? -You were fighting the other day too.
うち？ この間もケンカしてたし。
Yeah...I guess.
ああ　まあな。
You know, all fathers go through
あれだ　あの　どこの親父も→
a period of time when their daughters won't talk to them.
娘に　口　利いてもらえねえ 時期ってのがあんだろ。
During that period, my wife died,
うちは　ちょうど　そんときに かみさん死んじまってな。
and things just got worse.
余計　こじれちまって。
It's only just recently. That we got comfortable enough to fight.
いや　今になって　やっとだ。 ケンカできるようになった。
-I'm done eating. -Okay.
ごちそうさま。 はい。
Kaoru, you apologize to Hayato-kun today.
薫　今日は　ちゃんと 隼人君に謝んだぞ。
No. I'm not going to school.
やだ　学校　行かない。
It's best if you apologize and you two become close.
謝って仲良くできれば それが一番だろ。
I don't care if we don't get close.
仲良くしたくないもん。
Weren't you saying that someone who teases a friend is disgusting?
お前さ　友達をからかうやつなんて最低だって言ってたろ？
Then isn't someone who causes a friend to get hurt
じゃあさ　友達にケガさせといて 謝んねえやつは→
and refuse to apologize disgusting? That's the worst, isn't it?
最低じゃねえのか？　最低だろ。
I'm not the worst.
薫は最低じゃない。
"Oh-oh, you're gonna get abandoned."
《あ～あ　捨てられる》
"Marumo and Sasa Buta are gonna get separated."
《マルモと　ささブタは 離れ離れ》
I don't like people who won't accept advice.
素直になれないやつは嫌いだぞ。
But Hayato-ku said we...That Marumo would...
だって　隼人君　薫たちを。 マルモが薫たちを。
What did I do? Are you putting the blame on me?
あっ？　俺が何だよ。 俺のせいにすんのか？
But...
だって。
Forget it. Just be like that, you spoiled baby.
もういいよ。 ずっと　そうしてろ　甘ったれ。
Tomoki, we're going.
友樹　行くぞ。
I hate you, Marumo! I don't even want to see your face!
マルモなんか大嫌い！ マルモの顔なんて見たくない！
Oh, I see. I get it. Let's go.
ああ　そうか。　よ～く分かったよ。 行くぞ。
You're by yourself?
あれ？　１人？
Onee-chan didn't want to come to school.
うん。　お姉ちゃんは 学校　来たくないって。
It's because Hayato-kun gives her a hard time.
（まなみ）隼人君が いじめるからよ。
You're the worst.
（はるか）最低。
Kaoru-chan, I brought you lunch.
（彩）薫ちゃん　お昼　持ってきたよ。
Aya-chan.
彩ちゃん。
Hm? What?
（彩）んっ？　何？
Marumo and us are family, aren't we?
薫たちとマルモって 家族なんだよね。
Yes, didn't we talk about this before? You're living together so you're family.
（彩）うん　前にも話したでしょ？ 一緒に住んでるんだから家族だよ。
I wonder if we can keep on being together.
ずっと一緒にいられるのかな。
If we're separated, is that the end of our family?
もし別々になったら 家族は　おしまい？
What? What are you saying all of a sudden?
えっ？　急に　どうしたの？
Don't tell Marumo, okay?
マルモに言わない？
Okay.
（彩）うん。
Hayato-kun said we're going to get separated sooner or later.
隼人君がね　薫たちは そのうち離れ離れになるって。
He said that?
あっ　そんなこと。
Aya-chan, Marumo isn't our daddy.
彩ちゃん マルモはパパじゃないでしょ。
So if we're separated, is that the end of our family?
だから離れ離れになったら 家族は　もう　おしまいなの？
-Good night.
（社員）じゃ　お疲れさまでした。 （民子）お疲れさまです。
[I hate you, Marumo! I don't even want to see your face!]
《マルモなんか大嫌い！ マルモの顔なんて見たくない！》
[Oh, I see. I get it.]
《ああ　そうか。 よ～く分かったよ》
Takagi-kun, get that report done today please.
（民子）高木君 その報告書　今日中に上げてね。
Yes.
あっ　はい。
Takagi-kun?
高木君？ あっ。
Shiozawa-san, you have a child, don't you?
塩沢さんって　子供いるんすよね。
-I do. He's in high school. -High school, huh?
いるわよ　高校生。 高校生か。
When your child was in grade school,
お子さんが小学生のときって→
did he ever have problems at school and refuse to go?
トラブって　学校　行かないとか そういうのありました？
Why are you asking about that out of the blue?
何で　急に　そんなこと聞くの。
No, I just wondered.
いや　ちょっ　ちょっと。
Mine isn't very bright,
うちのは　頭　悪いからさ→
so he used to say he wasn't going to school because he didn't want to study.
勉強が嫌で　行かないとか休むとかよく言ってたけどね。
What did you do at times like that?
そういうときって どうしたんすか？
I'd buy him a new notebook. Nice and blank.
新しいノート買ってやんのよ。 真っさらの。
-Notebook? -Yes.
ノート？ そう。
Boys are pretty simple-minded, aren't they?
男の子なんて単純でしょ？
He must have felt smarter or something just because he got a brand new notebook.
ノートが新しくなっただけで　何か賢くなったような気がすんのかね。
It's like he got motivated suddenly and wanted to go to school.
急に　やる気　出しちゃって 学校　行きたくなっちゃうの。→
Isn't he stupid?
バカでしょ？
I see.  He is simple-minded.
ハハ　なるほど　ホント単純ですね。
Of course, that's what makes him so endearing too.
まあ　それがカワイイんだけどね。
I understand.
そうなんすよね。
Takagi-kun, you get motivated too and finish that up, okay?
高木君も　それ　やる気　出して 書き上げちゃってよ？→
I'm leaving first then.
じゃ　お先に失礼します。
Good night.
お疲れした。
What a nice story.
いや～　いい話だったね。
-What? -What Shiozawa-san was talking about right now.
えっ？ （鮫島）今の塩沢さんの話。→
It means that stationery isn't just supplies.
文具は　ただの道具じゃないって ことだよね。
It would be nice if there were stationery that's not just practical
実用性だけじゃなく 子供の背中を押すような→
but something exciting that would encourage children, don't you think?
わくわくとした文具が あるといいよね。→
I'll leave first then.
あっ　じゃ　お先。
Good night.
お疲れした。
Encourage...
背中を押すか。
Found them.
あった。
-Onee-chan, Marumo's late, isn't he? -Is he working overtime?
お姉ちゃん　マルモ遅いね。 残業かな。
Marumo doesn't have overtime. He said so before.
マルモは残業ないんだよ。 前に言ってたもん。
He should have been home long time ago. I wonder what happened.
とっくに帰ってくる時間なのに どうしたんだろ。
-Hello? -This is Aya.
もしもし？ [TEL]（彩）彩ですけど。
Oh, thank you for bringing Kaoru's lunch.
あっ　薫のお昼 ありがとうございました。
I'll make sure she goes to school tomorrow.
あしたは ちゃんと学校に行かせますから。
About that...
[TEL]そのことで　ちょっと。
-Yes? -She told me not to tell you, so
えっ？ [TEL]口止めされたんで→
I wasn't sure whether I should.
言おうか　どうか 迷ったんですけど。
What is it?
何ですか？
The reason Kaoru-chan didn't want to go to school
薫ちゃんが 学校に行きたくなかったのは→
wasn't just because she was being teased by a boy.
男の子に からかわれたことだけじゃなくて。
-What? -She was told that
えっ？ ホントの親子じゃないから→
since you're not the real dad, you won't be together for long,
ずっと一緒に暮らせないって 言われて→
and that's what upset her.
それを気にしてて。
Listen to what Kaoru-chan has to say when you get home, okay?
[TEL]薫ちゃんの話　後で ちゃんと聞いてあげてくださいね。
Good bye then.
[TEL]それじゃ。
Yes.
はい。
[It's a habit for the boys to tease the girls.]
《男子は 女子をからかうのが癖なの》
[You have to let it go. Just ignore it.]
《軽く受け流しゃいいんだよ。 無視しろ　無視》
[But Hayato-ku said we...That Marumo would...]
《だって　隼人君　薫たちを。 マルモが薫たちを》
[What did I do? Are you putting the blame on me?]
《俺が何だよ。 俺のせいにすんのか？》
[I hate you, Marumo! I don't even want to see your face!]
《マルモなんか大嫌い！ マルモの顔なんて見たくない！》
Looks just like Mook.
[TV]（ムック）かき氷器に…。 ムックに　そっくり。
Shaggy hair.
もじゃ毛。　もじゃ毛。
Onee-chan, what's wrong?
あれ？　お姉ちゃん　どうしたの？
Onee-chan.
お姉ちゃん。
Tomoki.
友樹。
What?
何？
Marumo's late, huh?
マルモ遅いね。
What should we do if Marumo doesn't come home anymore?
このまま　マルモが 帰ってこなかったら　どうする？
[Don't make more work for me. What are you doing?]
《余計なことしなくていいよ》 《お前　何やってんだよ　おい》
[What do you mean you didn't do anything wrong when you made him get hurt.]《
《ケガさしといて 悪くないってことないだろ》
[I'm really sorry.]
《ホントに　ごめんなさい》
[I hate you, Marumo! I don't even want to see your face!]
《マルモなんか大嫌い！ マルモの顔なんて見たくない！》
[Oh, I see. I get it.]
《ああ　そうか。 よ～く分かったよ》
I made trouble for Marumo at home and at school too.
おうちでも学校でも マルモのこと困らせちゃったし→
I even got into a fight so
ケンカもしちゃったし→
Marumo might not come home because of me.
薫のせいで　マルモ 帰ってこないかもしれない。
-What? -If he doesn't come home
えっ？ 帰ってこなかったら→
and we get separated,
別々になったら→
that's the end of our family. Because we're different.
家族は　おしまいなんだよ うちは特別だから。
No, I don't want that to happen.
嫌だよ　そんなの。
I won't be able to eat the food Marumo makes.
もう マルモのお料理　食べれなくなる。
He won't be sprinkling the goma shio boss, and
ごま塩の親分も 掛けてもらえないし→
he won't be playing catch with us.
キャッチボールも 教えてもらえない。
We'll never get better.
ずっと下手っぴのままかも。
I want to be with Marumo.
そんな　僕　マルモと一緒がいい。
I'm sorry, Tomoki.
友樹　ごめんね。
Onee-chan.
お姉ちゃん。
Kaoru, do you like Marumo?
薫　マルモのこと　好き？
-A lot. -Then all you have to do is apologize.
大好き。 だったら謝ればいいじゃん。
I want to apologize to Marumo. Let's go, Tomoki.
薫　マルモに謝りたい。 友樹　一緒に行こう。
Which way?
どっち？ う～ん→
When he doesn't come home, does he sleep at the office?
家に帰ってこないときは 会社で寝るのかな。
Then let's go to his office.
じゃ　会社　行こう。
Okay, the station's that way.
うん　駅は　あっち。
Which ticket do we buy?
幾らの切符　買えばいいのかな。
Let's go over there.
あっち行こう。 うん。
What are those guys doing?
何してんだ　あいつら。
There's a lot of stations.
駅　たくさんあるけど。
Where's Akebono Office Supplies?
あけぼの文具　どこだろ。
I don't know.
分かんない。
We should have learned how to ride trains, huh?
電車の乗り方 ちゃんと勉強すればよかったね。
We can't go to see Marumo by ourselves, can we?
やっぱり僕たちだけじゃ マルモのところ行けないね。
Tomoki, when Marumo comes home,
友樹　マルモが帰ってきたら→
let's help him out a lot, okay?
今度は いっぱい　お手伝いしようね。
Okay. We can't cook, but we can clean and do the laundry.
うん　ご飯は大変だけど お掃除とか　お洗濯とか。
Yeah. And we can't be fussy about our food.
うん　好き嫌いも駄目だからね。
Okay. I'll eat all my carrots too.
うん　ニンジンも　全部　食べる。
I hope Marumo comes home.
マルモ　帰ってきてくれるかな。
I'll have to apologize when I see Marumo.
マルモに会ったら ちゃんと謝らないと。
Like how Marumo did with Hayato-kun. Bow properly like this.
マルモが隼人君にしたみたいに ちゃんと　お辞儀して　こうやって。
Marumo, I'm sorry for burning the breakfast.
マルモ　朝ご飯　真っ黒にして ごめんなさい。
Marumo, I'm sorry for not apologizing to Hayato-kun.
マルモ　隼人君に謝らなくて
Marumo, I'm sorry for saying that I hate you.
マルモ 大嫌いって言って　ごめんなさい。
And, and...
それから　それから。
Kaoru, Tomoki.
薫　友樹。
Where are you guys going?
お前ら　どこ行く気だよ。
Marumo.
マルモ。
Sorry.
ごめんね。
Hey, hey, why are you crying?
おいおい　お前ら お前ら　どうして泣いてんだ。
We were afraid Marumo wasn't coming home.
マルモが帰ってこなくて 怖かったから。
Of course I'm coming home.
帰るに決まってんだろ？
I don't have any place else to go home to.
俺は　ほかに 帰るとこなんかねえんだから。
You guys too.
お前らも同じ。
The 2nd floor of Kujira is all we have.
俺たちには クジラの２階しかないんだ。
But Marumo, you don't like Kaoru, right?
でも マルモ　薫のこと嫌いでしょ？
Let's see. There could be times
どうだろうな。　もしかしたら→
that I may think I don't like you.
嫌いって思うときも あるかもしんねえな。
That's what I thought.
やっぱり。
If you don't like me, we can't live together, right?
もし嫌いになったら 一緒に住めないよね。
We'll be separated.
離れ離れだよね。
What? What are you saying.
はっ？　何　言ってんだよ。
Of course we'll still be together even if we don't like each other at times.
嫌いになっても 一緒にいるに決まってんだろ？
-Why? -Because we're family.
どうして？ 俺たちは家族だから。
Stay together if you like each other and go our separate ways if you don't.
好きだから一緒 嫌いだから別々なんて→
A family isn't something that should be taken lightly like that.
家族は そんな甘えもんじゃねえんだよ。
To stay together whether you like it or not, that's what family's all about.
好きでも嫌いでも 離れられないのが家族なんだ。
Even when Kaoru grows up and says things like "Marumo, you smell,"
薫が　でっかくなって 「マルモ　臭え」とか言っても→
I won't go away, and when Tomoki grows up
離れないし 友樹が　でっかくなって→
and says things like "Marumo, you're super annoying," you can forget about it.
「マルモ　超うぜえ」とか言っても 無駄だ。
Because we're family.
俺たちは家族だから。
What was that.
（薫・友樹）何それ。
Anyway, we'll always be together.
とにかく　ずっと一緒にいる。
I'm glad.
（薫・友樹）よかった。
Okay, let's go home then.
よし　分かったら　ほら　帰るぞ。
Look. I was late because I was making these.
ほら これ作ってたら遅くなっちった。
Open it and see.
開けてみ。 うん。
Did you make these, Marumo?
マルモが作ったの？
There were a lot of these unsold erasers at the office. My failed idea.
会社にさ　売れ残った消しゴムが いっぱい余っててさ。　俺の失敗作。
I used those and tried making some hand-made stamps.
それ使って　手作りスタンプセット試しに手作りで作ってみた。
-I made them for you. -Thank you.
お前にやろうと思って。 ありがとう。
Try it.
押してみ。 うん。
Cute.
カワイイ。
Is this Mook? He's big.
これムック？　おっきいね。
There's Marumo and Onee-chan, and who's this?
あと　マルモと　お姉ちゃんと あれ？　これ誰だろう。
-That's you. -He looks like me.
お前だよ。 似てる。
It's a family stamp. See, we're all together.
家族スタンプ。 なっ　ほら　みんな一緒だろ？
Then here's today's okite.
じゃ　今日のおきてだ。
Whether you like it or not, we're family.
好きでも嫌いでも　家族。
Alright.
よし。
Okay, let's go to sleep now.
よし　じゃ　寝るぞ。
Good night.
おやすみ。
I want to sleep with Marumo.
薫　マルモと一緒に寝たい。
-Me too. -Wait, wait, the three of us
僕も。 ちょっと　ちょっと　３人なんて→
can't fit in here. Hey, wait.
無理に決まってんだろ おい　ちょっと。
Hey, no, no, you're falling off. Wait...
おい　駄目　駄目だ　はみ出るぞ。 おい　ちょっと…。
We'll be okay.
大丈夫だもん。
No, no, no, hey. It's too cramped.
いや　いや　いや　いや　ちょっ せっ　狭い　狭いよ。
-It's cramped. -No it's not.
狭い。 狭くない。
-It's hot.
暑いよ。 暑くない。
Excuse me.
あの。 んっ？
Looks like you're having fun, so let me join in too.
せっかくなんで　お邪魔します。
Wait, wait. No, no more.
ちょっと　ちょちょっ いや　もう無理だ→
No, no, no, no.
あっ　無理　無理　無理　無理。
That tickles. That tickles.
くすぐったい。　くすぐったい。
Mook, Moo... Get away from there, Mook.
ムック　ムッ…　あっ そこ　そこは　ちょっ　ムック→
Don't thrash around in there, Mook.
そこで暴れるなムック アハ　ちょっと。
-Good morning. -Good morning, Kaoru-chan.
おはよう。 （はるか）薫ちゃん　おはよう。
Hayato-kun, I'm sorry for making you get hurt.
隼人君 ケガさせちゃって　ごめんなさい。
Marumo taught me how to apologize
マルモが 謝り方　教えてくれたから→
so I'm just practicing.
練習しただけだよ。
Sasakura-san, I'm sorry for teasing you.
笹倉さん からかって　ごめんなさい。
This is just practice too.
これも練習だけどね。
You don't have a choice, Hayato-kun,
仕方ないよ　だって隼人君→
since you like Onee-chan, right?
お姉ちゃんのこと 好きなんでしょ？
What? What are you saying?
はっ？　何　言ってんの？
Marumo told us that
だって　マルモが言ってたよ。
boys tease girls they like.
男は　好きな女の子を からかうもんだって。
So that must mean Hayato-kun likes Onee-chan.
だから隼人君は お姉ちゃんのことが好きなんだよ。
I don't like her.
好きじゃないよ。
Oh, Hayato-kun, you must like her.
（はるか）あっ　隼人君　好きなんだ。
-He's turning red. -He is.
（まなみ）赤くなってる。 ホントだ。
Look, he's turning red, red, red.
（まなみ）ねっ　なってる 赤い　赤い　赤い。
Marumo made it for us. Family stamp.
マルモが作ってくれたんだよ 家族スタンプ。
-What's that. -That's so cute.
何それ。 （まなみ）カワイイ。
Isn't it? Isn't it?
でしょ　でしょ。 （はるか）いいな～。
Then one more.
じゃ　もう一つ。
Quit it.
やめろよ。
Wait.
待って。
Hey, don't run around in the classroom.
（杉下）あっ　こら 教室で走るんじゃない。
Let's get begin the class. Everyone get back to your desk.
じゃ　授業　始めるぞ。 みんな　席に着いて。
What's that?
（鮫島）何それ。 はっ。
Huh? What? What?
（鮫島）えっ？　何　何。
Remember that first complaint I took?
いえ　あっ　最初のクレーム あったじゃないすか。
That woman who used the cap as a ear cleaner and bled.
キャップで耳かきして 出血した　おばはんの。
Oh, yeah, I remember.
（鮫島）ああ　あったね。
I was wondering
あのおばはん→
if that woman would be agreeable if there was a pen like this.
もし　こんなペンがあったら 納得するかと思いまして。
-What? -No, it was just an absurd idea...
（鮫島）えっ？ いえいえ　これはバカバカしい…。
No, no.
（鮫島）いや　いや　いや　いや。
That's interesting.
面白いね。
Write it up in a proposal and submit it to me.
これ　ちゃんと企画書に書いて 見せて。
I'll be looking forward to it.
楽しみにしてるよ。
Coach Marumo. Please train us.
（友樹・薫）マルモ監督 お願いします。
Okay, here it goes.
よし　いくぞ。
What was that.
（友樹・薫）あっ。 あっ　何だよ。
However, I'll give you credit for going all out to go after the ball.
ただし　全力で球を追い掛ける姿勢ナイス。
Thank you, Coach Marumo.
ありがとうございます マルモ監督。
Here we go.
いくぞ。
Oh, there's Hayato-kun.
あっ　隼人君だ。
Okay, next up is Athlete Hayato. Let's go for it.
よし　じゃ　次は隼人選手。 張り切って　いってみよう。
-You're hopeless. -How do you expect to catch a ball just standing there.
下手くそ。 そんな棒立ちじゃ捕れねえよ。
-Come here, we're gonna practice. -Come on.
練習するから　こっち来い。 おいで。
Come on, Hayato-kun.
来て　隼人君。
Coach Marumo, please train us.
（３人）マルモ監督　お願いします。
Okay then, next is fly ball.
お願いします。 じゃ　次は　フライいくぞ。
Who's gonna get that. Call for it. Go, Kaoru.
それ。　誰だ　誰が捕るんだ。 声　出せ　声。　いけ　薫。
-Mamoru-kun, long time no see. -What happened, Sasakura-san?
（秋人）護君　久しぶり。 いえ　笹倉さん　どうしたんすか？
-Sorry for just showing up.
（秋人）ああ　急に　ごめんね。 いえ。
Truth of the matter is, the twins' mother contacted me.
（秋人）実は　双子の母親が 急に連絡よこしてさ。
Ayumi-san did?
あゆみさんが？
She found out somehow that
純一郎が亡くなったこと→
Junichirou passed away.
彼女の耳にも 入っちまったらしくて。
And she's saying she wants to see the twins.
（秋人）それで ２人に会いたいって言うんだよ。
I see.
そうですか。
I didn't know what to say.
もう　参っちゃったよ。→
Of course, I told her she couldn't, but I thought I'd at least let you know.
もちろん断ったけどさ　一応 護君の耳にも入れとこうと思って。
I see. I understand.
あっ　そうですか。　分かりました。